<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Unfiled | My Octopress Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://ayl.github.io/blog/categories/unfiled/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://ayl.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-03-21T09:10:18-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://ayl.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Your Name]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Arrays]]></title>
    <link href="http://ayl.github.io/blog/2006/09/20/arrays/"/>
    <updated>2006-09-20T20:45:21-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://ayl.github.io/blog/2006/09/20/arrays</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><H3 id="toc">Table of Contents</H3><OL><LI><A HREF="#arrays">Arrays</A></LI></OL><H3 id="arrays">Arrays</H3><P>Before heading into the control flow that PHP has to offer, I thought it would be important to talk a bit about how arrays work in PHP. In PHP, the simplest way to think about every array is that they are essentially associative arrays. That is to say that every entry in the array has an associated key and value pair. This is not so different from the way that Perl arrays work, but there is one crucial difference.</P><P>The difference is that in PHP, there is no use of the 'at' symbol (<TT>@</TT>) for any meaning. Instead, you simply treat arrays like any other variable with the dollar symbol (<TT>$</TT>). That said, let's move on to some examples of how arrays work.</P><PRE><br />
1.  &lt;?php<br />
2.    $pi = array( 3, 1, 4, 1, 5, 9, 2, 6, 5, 3, 5, 8, 9 );<br />
3.<br />
4.    print_r($pi);<br />
5.    print("The first few digits of pi are:"<br />
6.           .$pi[0].$pi[1].$pi[2].$pi[3].$pi[4]."&lt;BR&gt;");<br />
7.<br />
8.    $fruitcolors = array(<br />
9.                     "bannana" =&gt; "yellow",<br />
10.                    "orange"  =&gt; "orange",<br />
11.                    "apple"   =&gt; "red");<br />
12.<br />
13.   print("The color of an apple is "<br />
14.         .$fruitcolors['apple']."&lt;BR&gt;");<br />
15.<br />
16. ?&gt;<br />
</PRE><P>First thing that you should notice is that arrays are handled in nearly the same manner as other languages in that you enclose the key with a set of square brackets (<TT>[]</TT>). Line 2 is the creation of an array using the function <A HREF=http://www.php.net/manual/en/function.array.php>array</A>. This function simply returns an array with automatic indexing if no index is provided as in Line 2. The <A HREF=http://www.php.net/manual/en/function.print-r.php>print_r</A> function is used to print the array in Line 4, and in Line 5, the way to access the elements of the array are shown. As I said before, the method is identical to many other programming languages. </P><P>In Lines 8-11, the array <TT>$fruitcolors</TT> is created. This time, automatic indexing is not used because the indices are provided ("bannana", "orange", and "apple"). These become the keys and the repective colors become the values. The symbol <TT>=&gt;</TT> is used to associate the key from the value and the delimiter is obviously the comma (<TT>,</TT>), used to separate the<br />
key/value pairs. Line 13-14 show how to retrieve a value with a given key. </P><P>PHP supports multi-dimensional arrays by simply allowing you to put arrays within other arrays. This is illustrated below:</P><PRE><br />
1.  &lt;?php<br />
2.<br />
3.   $matrix = array(array(1, 2), array(3, 4));<br />
4.<br />
5.   print("Matrix value at position 1, 2 is:<br />
6.            ".$matrix[1][2]."&lt;BR&gt;);<br />
7.<br />
8.  ?&gt;<br />
</PRE><P>The multi-dimensional array is created using multiple calls to <TT>array</TT>. Line 3 simply creates a 2x2 matrix with the values 1, 2 in the first row, and 3, 4 in the second. Lines 5-6 show how to access the values within multi-dimensional arrays using two indices.</P><P>As you can see, the array implementation in PHP is both flexible and powerful. Coupled with the vast number of built-in functions that PHP provides to handle arrays, they are a very useful data structure. The size of an array is also dynamic, which is a nice change from the static arrays from C.</P></p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Basics]]></title>
    <link href="http://ayl.github.io/blog/2006/09/20/introduction/"/>
    <updated>2006-09-20T20:38:47-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://ayl.github.io/blog/2006/09/20/introduction</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<br />


<h3 id="toc">Table of Contents</h3>


<ol>
<li><a href="#basics">Basics</a></li>
<li><a href="#commenting">Commenting</a></li>
<li><a href="#variables">Variables</a></li>
<li><a href="#functions">Function Calling</a></li>
<li><a href="#arrays">Arrays</a></li>
<li><a href="#conditionals">Conditionals</a>
<ul>
<li><a href="#cond_struct">Structure of a Conditional</a></li>
<li><a href="#cond_oper">Conditional Operators</a></li>
<li><a href="#cond_if">IF</a></li>
<li><a href="#cond_switch">SWITCH</a></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><a href="#loop">Loop Structures</a>
<ul>
<li><a href="#loop_for">FOR</a></li>
<li><a href="#loop_while">WHILE</a></li>
<li><a href="#loop_foreach">FOREACH</a></li>
</ul>
</li>
</ol>


<h3 id="basics">Basics:</h3>


<p>PHP is unique in that it is a Hypertext <strong>Parser</strong> and not just a language. Hence PHP interfaces with HTML very very easily. In<br />
fact it interfaces with HTML so easily that you can copy over any existing HTML page and change the extension to ".php" or ".cgi" and<br />
it will still work. This is because PHP code itself only works within a certain kind of tag. For example:</p>


<pre>1. 
 2. 
<title>Hello World!</title> 3. 
 4. 
 5.
 6.      
 7.              //PHP code goes here
 8.      ?&gt;
 9. 
 10</pre>


<p>As you can see in the above example, PHP code will only run inside the <tt> and <tt>?&gt;</tt> tags. Everything outside of those tags, PHP will simply be printed out. This allows for PHP to be incorporated in already existing webpages with great ease.</p>


<h3 id="commenting"><tt>Commenting:</tt></h3>


<p>Because of CS50 (Introduction to Computer Science), the heavenly mandate that demands commenting has been drilled thoroughly into me. Thus, I find it imperative to explain commenting first. It is also one of the easiest topics to cover and necessary to many things.</p>


<p>If you were a careful reader you would have noticed that I used a comment in the above code. The commenting style in PHP is identical<br />
to many other languages, namely C++ and Java. Hence, both <tt>//</tt> and <tt>/*   */</tt> works in the exact same way.</p>


<p>Another way to comment is with the <tt>#</tt> like in Perl or UNIX shell scripting. Here is an example of commenting:</p>


<pre><tt>
 1. &lt;?php 
 2.      // This is a Java/C++ style comment.
 3.
 4.      /* This is also a comment in C style.
 5.         This is inside the comment block. */
 6.
 7.      # This is a Perl style comment.
 8. ?&gt;
</tt></pre>


<p>One thing to keep in mind is this: <strong>Like many other programming languages, every non-comment line must end with a semicolon (<tt>;</tt>) !!!</strong> It is a stupid point if you know it already, but if you don't you'll be thoroughly confused by parser errors.</p>


<h3 id="variables">Variables:</h3>


<p>In PHP, variables are handled in a very convenient manner. It is not like C or C++ where you have to worry alot about the datatypes of all of your variables and have to declare all of your variables. In PHP, variables are handled more like Java and exactly like Perl (except for one minor difference which will be explained later). Variables can be declared <strong>anywhere</strong>. You also do not have to worry about datatypes, as PHP will try to convert any datatype into anyother datatype when necessary.</p>


<p>Variables in PHP are demarked with a dollar (<tt>$</tt>). In other words, every variable must start with a <tt>$</tt>. This is what tells the PHP parser to consider the next word to be a variable.</p>


<p>Rather than try to explain all the things that you can do with variables, I will give you an example and show you how it works.</p>


<pre><tt>
 1. &lt;?php
 2.  $n1 = 1;   // The numerical value 1 =&gt; n1
 3.  $n2 = 3.5; // The numerical value 3.5 =&gt; n2
 4.  $a = 10;   // 10 is stored to a
 5.  $b = "Hello world!!"; // "Hello world!!" =&gt; b
 6.  $c = $b." Hi!";       // "Hello world!! Hi!"
 7.                        //   is stored to c
 8.  $d = "Ten is ".$a;    // "Ten is 10" =&gt; d
 9.  $e = "Ten is $a.";    // "Ten is 10." =&gt; e
 10 ?&gt;
</tt></pre>


<p>There are basically only two datatypes that one will really needs to be worried about: Numerical datatypes and Strings. Numerical<br />
datatypes are simply numbers including <tt>int</tt> and <tt>float</tt>. Strings are anything enclosed within a set of quotes. Lines 1-5 in the above example show the setting of both numerical and string variables.</p>


<p>In Lines 6-8, a very strange thing is happening (if you don't know Perl). Line 6 reads: <tt>$c = $b." Hello again!";</tt>. This line takes the value of <tt>$b</tt> and uses the dot operator (<tt>.</tt>) to concatenate the two strings together. In Line 8, something that is very different from C occurs: The numerical value 10 is automatically converted to a string datatype! Thus PHP handles the conversion of numerical datatypes to strings inherently.</p>


<p><tt>In Line 9, the perferable method of inserting another variable's<br />
value into another string is used. Within the set of quotes, any<br />
variable will be evaluated, and its value is converted and inserted<br />
into the string. Hence the variable <tt>$e</tt> will have the value<br />
"Ten is 10." Note the period at the end of the string! The<br />
equivalent, of course, could have been achieved in Line 8 with:<br />
<tt>$d = "Ten is ".$a.".";</tt> But this is much harder to read than<br />
Line 9.</tt></p>


<p><tt><br />
</tt><tt><strong>Stylistic note:</strong> I prefer using the dot operator only when<br />
using the return value from a function to incorporate into a string<br />
(more on this later) and when concatenating the value of arrays<br />
together. In all other cases, I usually evaluate them inside the<br />
string. Because beauty is in the eye of the beholder, you are left<br />
to your own discretion, but this is the convention that I will try<br />
to follow from now forth.</tt></p>


<p><tt><br />
</tt><tt>One interesting feature of PHP that I had neglected to included but<br />
was reminded by Blake Johnson is that there is a convenient way to print<br />
variables inside HTML code. Here is an example:</tt></p>


<p><tt>       </tt></p>


<pre><tt>
 1.  2.  $n1 = 1;   // The numerical value 1 =&gt; n1
 3. ?&gt;
 4.
 5. </tt>
<h1><tt>The value of $n1:  </tt></h1>
<tt>
        </tt></pre>


<p><tt><br />
Using the synatx <tt></tt>, we can immediately<br />
insert the value of the variable into the HTML code.</tt><tt>       </tt></p>


<h3 id="functions"><tt>Function Calling:</tt></h3>


<p><tt>       </tt></p>


<p><tt>I won't spend too much time on this, as it should be completely<br />
self-evident if you know a bit about programming. Basically,<br />
any word that does not have a special character in front of it will<br />
be considered a function. The arguments following the command must<br />
be enclosed in parenthesis. (There are a few exceptions, such as<br />
<tt>print</tt> whose parenthesis are completely optional. However,<br />
for the sake of consistency, it is nice to enclose the arguments to<br />
any function with parenthesis. People who learned Perl first will<br />
argue with me and will more than likely use the syntax that they are<br />
most familiar with.)</tt></p>


<p><tt><br />
</tt><tt>So let us do some function calling.</tt></p>


<p><tt><br />
</tt></p>


<pre><tt>
 1.  2.
 3.  print("hello world
");
 4.
 5.  $a = file("temp.txt");
 6.
 7.  $b = "<strong> &lt; &lt; &lt; &lt;";
 8.  print("  ".htmlentities($a)." ");
 9.
 10 ?&gt;</strong></tt><tt><strong>       </strong></tt></pre>


<p><tt><strong><br />
</strong></tt><tt><strong>In this example, we find see the function <tt>print</tt> in Line<br />
3 being called to print out HTML code. In Line 5, we find that the<br />
function <tt>file</tt> is called, and the array that it returns is<br />
stored into the variable <tt>$a</tt> (more on arrays later). In<br />
Line 8, we find that the return value of the function<br />
<tt>htmlentities</tt> is being concatenated with the dot operator to<br />
become enclosed within a set of HTML tags. </strong></tt></p>


<p><tt><strong>       </strong></tt></p>


<p><tt><strong>So you may be asking yourself what exactly do these functions do?<br />
This is beyond the scope of this tutorial. The aim of this tutorial<br />
is to provide you with enough of the basics of PHP to begin coding<br />
in it armed with only the PHP documentation. That said, I will show<br />
you how you can use the documentation to understand how these<br />
functions work.</strong></tt></p>


<p><tt><strong><br />
</strong></tt></p>


<ol><tt><strong><br />
</strong></tt></p>
<li><tt><strong>First go to the <a href="http://www.php.net/manual/en/funcref.php"><br />
PHP function reference</a>. </strong></tt></li>
<p><tt><strong><br />
</strong></tt></p>
<li><tt><strong>Once there, you have a few options:</strong></tt>
<ul><tt><strong><br />
</strong></tt></p>
<li><tt><strong>In the upper left corner, there is a text field labeled<br />
"lookup:" Here you can type the name of the function about which<br />
you wish to know more.</strong></tt></li>
<p><tt><strong>               </strong></tt></p>
<li><tt><strong>If you are seeking for a function to perform a certain task,<br />
then look through the Table of Contents to find the task that<br />
you are interested in and view all the available functions<br />
related to that task. For instance, the function<br />
<tt>htmlentities</tt> can be found under "String Functions."</strong></tt></li>
<p><tt><strong><br />
</strong></tt></ul>
</li>
<p><tt><strong><br />
</strong></tt><tt><strong><br />
</strong></tt></p>
<li><tt><strong>After finding the function that you are interested in, look at<br />
the function description to understand how the function works and<br />
more importantly see if the function is supported in the version and<br />
compiled options of PHP that you have (see<br />
<a href="http://ayl.nuwen.net/wp-admin/php3.html#phpinfo">Appendix</a> for details)</strong></tt></li>
<p><tt><strong><br />
</strong></tt></ol>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[PHP Tutorial]]></title>
    <link href="http://ayl.github.io/blog/2006/09/20/test-page-2/"/>
    <updated>2006-09-20T17:57:45-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://ayl.github.io/blog/2006/09/20/test-page-2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><H3 id="intro">Introduction:</H3><P>PHP (PHP: Hypertext Processor) is a web programming language that is extremely versatile and fast. It is basically a general-purpose scripting language designed for the Internet. It has recently become the mostly used Apache web module, and its use has grown nearly exponentially. In short, it is a very good language to know if you are trying to do any kind of web programming</P><P>PHP is a language that is most similar to Perl. In fact, most of PHP's syntax is identical to Perl in nearly every way possible. I have a sneaking suspicion that a lot of Perl code was used in the making of PHP. Before the advent of PHP, Perl was very often used to write CGI scripts, but the  way that Perl handles various aspects of CGI like retrieving POST and GET fields are far more inconvenient than PHP.</P><H3 id="about">About this tutorial:</H3><P>This tutorial is not for the casual webdesigner who is used to WYSIWYG programs to design their webpages. This tutorial assumes that you are familiar with writing HTML code by hand and know basic computer programming concepts such as conditionals, loops, and data types. If you do not know these concepts, then I suggest that you learn them before continuing your endeavor to learn PHP.</P><P>This tutorial is geared towards the functional uses of PHP and showing the vast library of functions that PHP has to offer. It is the goal of this tutorial to provide you with the basic knowledge necessary to begin programming in PHP and only need to refer to <A HREF="http://www.php.net">www.php.net</A> for assistance.</P><P>Then, without further ado, let us begin!</P></p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Projects]]></title>
    <link href="http://ayl.github.io/blog/2006/09/20/projects/"/>
    <updated>2006-09-20T16:11:25-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://ayl.github.io/blog/2006/09/20/projects</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Personal projects of my random hobbies!</p>


<p>Choose a tutorial or project description from the right.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
