<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Life In General | aaronylee]]></title>
  <link href="http://ayl.github.io/blog/categories/life-in-general/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://ayl.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-03-21T09:43:48-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://ayl.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Aaron Lee]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[hello new york!]]></title>
    <link href="http://ayl.github.io/blog/2008/02/11/hello-new-york/"/>
    <updated>2008-02-11T01:35:56-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://ayl.github.io/blog/2008/02/11/hello-new-york</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My recent trip to the Big Apple albeit brief has left me pining for more gustatory pleasures the moment I stepped on the plane bound for my St Louis home. While I knew before I arrived that New York provided the roof of the world's cultural foods, I was surprised by the depth of cultures present from block to block. Walking into K-town was as seamless teleportation to the hustle and bustle of the streets of Seoul with signs spilling down with Korean script, then abruptly ending back into the American starkness.</p>


<p>Perhaps it was the company of old friends or perhaps it was my preconceived belief of the coldness of the New Yorker, but I was again surprised to find warmth and hidden smiles under a demeanor, tempered by the cold strong winds whipping through the streets and by the temperamental market. Walking through Central Park, with its apologetically large number of trees, I found dwellers collectively finding solace from the confines of the concrete prisons of their homes.</p>


<p>Though comparatively the congenial suburbs of my youth pale in the vastness of the City, I found myself hoping to find my way back again, if only for the sake of my palate.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[lockin pics]]></title>
    <link href="http://ayl.github.io/blog/2008/02/05/lockin-pics/"/>
    <updated>2008-02-05T11:11:04-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://ayl.github.io/blog/2008/02/05/lockin-pics</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>For all the people at GPC, I've posted the Lockin pictures from this past weekend online here:</p>


<p><a href="http://picasaweb.google.com/gpcbereans2008/BereansGFLockIn2008?authkey=wQ-YA4CyBMg">GPC Picasa Album</a></p>


<p>Props go to Joyce for some of the shots.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[what ive been doing with my free time...]]></title>
    <link href="http://ayl.github.io/blog/2008/01/14/what-ive-been-doing-with-my-free-time/"/>
    <updated>2008-01-14T22:41:53-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://ayl.github.io/blog/2008/01/14/what-ive-been-doing-with-my-free-time</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In case people have been wondering what the heck I've been up to. Here it is...</p>


<p><a href="http://ayl.nuwen.net/index.php/projects/diy-imod-ipod/">iMod iPod DIY tutorial</a></p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[premonitions...]]></title>
    <link href="http://ayl.github.io/blog/2007/12/11/premonitions/"/>
    <updated>2007-12-11T20:52:29-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://ayl.github.io/blog/2007/12/11/premonitions</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Yesterday I found myself sliding into a truck that sudden stopped. Under normal conditions, the 15-feet distance and my remarkable reflexes would have been more than enough to stop at an adequate distance behind her, but unfortunately I felt the tires begin to slide due to the slippery conditions. It's a strange feeling watching the inevitable happen without a thing that you can do to stop it.</p>


<p>Earlier that morning, I had three separate occasions that I was positive that I was going to get into an accident. First, I was stopped at a corner and a car was making a right turn into the opposite lane and came within an inch of hitting my car. Further down that same street another car was backing out into the street but we had no vision of each other and he almost backed into me. Finally as I turning into the parking lot, an SUV was making a U-turn and blocked the vision of the opposite lane. Thinking that the lane was clear, I began to turn left into the lot when I spotted the small car behind it that was already moving.</p>


<p>I remember having a funny feeling that something bad was going to happen and that I should be really careful. Should have listened more to my gut instincts...</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[starry, starry night...]]></title>
    <link href="http://ayl.github.io/blog/2007/10/13/starry-starry-night/"/>
    <updated>2007-10-13T14:58:40-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://ayl.github.io/blog/2007/10/13/starry-starry-night</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://ayl.nuwen.net/wp-content/uploads/2007/10/starry-night-mid.jpg" rel="lightbox"  title="mid"><img src="http://ayl.nuwen.net/wp-content/uploads/2007/10/starry-night-small.jpg" alt="mid" /></a></p>


<p>Taken during the 2007 camping trip last night!</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
